Guide to the Coalition to Stop Trident Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Organizational Records, Series I
  - Trident system files
    - Electric Boat Shipyard [Groton, Connecticut]
      - The Day [New London, Connecticut; re: news blackout], 1981 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      - Employee lay-offs, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - Employee strike, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - Fact sheets and general clippings, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      - Painters union, Local 1503 [re: hazardous working conditions], 1978 (Box 5, Folder 105)
      - Proescher, Richard [fired Electric Boat employee], 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - GD World [General Dynamics Corporation newsletter], 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - "Submarine History Highlights 1900-1983", undated (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Trident Missiles I and II, 1977-1983 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Trident submarines
      - DMS profiles [statistics and data about Trident submarines], undated (Box 5, Folder 110)
      - Fact sheets, undated (Box 5, Folder 111)
      - General clippings, 1972-1984 (Box 5, Folder 112-113)
      - Position papers, 1977-1983 (Box 5, Folder 114)
      - Published photographs and graphics, 1979-1980, undated (Box 5, Folder 115)
      - Technical explanations, 1982-1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 116)
- Subject Files, Series II
  Arranged alphabetically, the Subject Files are a varied and not comprehensive source for topics, events, and groups relating to the disarmament movement on a national and international level. Materials include newsletters, flyers, mailings, and speeches. Although these records span from 1969 to 1993, the bulk falls between 1977 and 1989. These materials were collected by members of the Coalition to Stop Trident and other local groups and were used to support their anti-nuclear work. They serve to place the anti-Trident activism in Connecticut within a context of broader anti-nuclear movements. The researcher should be cautioned, however, that the materials represent only a sampling of those from the world-wide disarmament movement of the 1970s and 1980s.
  - Alternative Employment Study Group [Scotland, England], 1988, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Bay State Center for Economic Conversion [Cambridge, Massachusetts], 1983-1984, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament [London, England], 1986-1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Catholic Peace Fellowship [New York, NY], undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Center for Defense Information [Washington, DC], 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Center for Peace and Contact [Mütlangen, Germany], 1986-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Coalition for a New Foreign Military Policy [Washington, DC], 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Continental Walk for Disarmament and Social Justice [organizing manual], 1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Defense industry, 1978-1985, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Democracy and Weapons: A Bill of Rights for Citizens in the Shadows of America's Nuclear Weapons Production Facilities" (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Department of Energy [closings of nuclear power plants], 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Economic conversion, 1976-1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "First Strike" policy, 1982-1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - From Trident to Life Campaign [King's Bay, Georgia], 1986-1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Gensuiken News [Tokyo, Japan], 1987 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Greenpeace, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Ground Zero Center for Non-violent Action [Poulsboro, Washington]
    - Flyers and mailings, 1981-1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Newsletter, 1982-1989 (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
  - INFACT [Boston, Massachusetts], 1986 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Interhelp: A Networking Newsletter [Northampton, Massachusetts], 1986 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - International anti-Trident work, 1984-1994, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - King's Bay, Georgia [submarine base], 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Lawyers' Committee on Nuclear Policy [New York, New York], 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Mobilization for Survival, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - New Age [Manchester, New Hampshire], 1978 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - North Atlantic Network [international disarmament group], 1985-1988 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Nuclear disarmament
    - Cartoons, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Church involvement, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Nuclear Free and Independent Pacific [International disarmament group], 1983-1993 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Nuclear Resister: Newsletter of the National No-Nukes Prison Support Collective [Tempe, Arizona], 1983 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Pacific Peacemaker [Seattle, Washington]
    - Flyers and mailings, 1977, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Newsletters, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Plowshare Press [Mountain View, California], 1977, 1982-1990 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - RECON [Philadelphia, Pennsylvania], 1979 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - The Round Table [St. Louis, Missouri], 1987 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Sante Fe Peace Coalition [Sante Fe, New Mexico], 1984 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Shinsei [Tokyo, Japan], 1986 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Stop the B-1 Bomber/ National Peace Conversion Campaign, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Stop Project ELF [Madison, Wisconsin], 1981-1994 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - "Swords into Plowshares" [speech delivered by Walter P. Reuther to the Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare] (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Teach-ins on college campuses, 1981 November 11 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Union of Concerned Scientists [briefing papers], 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - United Nuclear [Montville, Connecticut nuclear power plant], 1974-1980, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Women Strike for Peace [Washington, DC], 1980 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - WIN [Workshop in Non-violence, New York, New York], 1976 (Box 8, Folder 46)
- Visual Materials, 1981, undated; Series III
  Visual Materials contains photographs, a slide presentation, and exhibit posters. The photographs were taken in 1981 of protestors demonstrating against the sea trials and commissioning of the USS Ohio, the first Trident submarine. The Slide presentation was created by the CST to educate the public on the hazards of nuclear weapons and it includes both the script and slides. The Exhibit posters include photographs from demonstrations against Trident submarines accompanied by text which describes the events and anti-Trident work. The origin of these posters is unknown.
  - Photographs
    - USS Ohio launching, 1979 April 7 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - USS Ohio sea trials, 1981 June (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Slide presentation, undated
    - Scripts (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Slides (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Exhibit Posters, undated (Box 10)
- Additional Material, Accession 1998-M-100
  Arranged alphabetically, the addition includes correspondence, memoranda, publications, clippings, flyers, and other materials relating to the Coalition to Stop Trident and other local and national groups working to stop the production of nuclear weapons. The CST files from the main accession are supplemented by the "Statement on Disbandment," which gives the rationale behind the break-up of the group in 1989. Other files include a useful chronology of demonstrations against the Trident program, as well as a paper reflecting on the use of civil disobedience as a means of protest against Trident. The addition also documents the group, Witness for Disarmament, which was a member of the CST and continued to protest against the Trident program after the CST disbanded. Two folders of materials on the Plowshares movement, including chronologies of Plowshares actions, continue documentation found in the main accession. Clippings concerning the Electric Boat Corporation, the construction of Trident and other submarines, and the United States Department of Defense provide background information. Publications, flyers, clippings, newsletters, and other materials from related anti- nuclear groups serve to place the work of the CST and other local groups into a broader national and international movement against nuclear weapons.
  - Abalone Alliance Legal Collective [San Luis Obispo, CA], 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ¡Basta!: No Mandate for War: A Pledge of Resistance Handbook, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Coalition to Stop Trident
    - Chronology of demonstrations, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Civil Disobedience and Trident: Some Reflections", 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Statement upon disbanding, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Connecticut Freeze Campaign [Hartford, CT], 1985-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Democracy and Weaponry: A Bill of Rights for Citizens in the Shadows of America's Nuclear Weapons Production Facilities", 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Electric Boat Company [Groton, CT], 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation [Nyack, NY], 1989-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - From Trident to Life [Decatur, GA], 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Greenpeace [Washington, DC], 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kobasa, Stephen [member of the Coalition to Stop Trident and Witness for Disarmament]
    - Court case, 1987-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Laffin, Art ["Faithful Versus Effective Action;" speech], 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Lawyer's Committee on Nuclear Policy [New York, NY], 1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Livermore Action Group [Berkeley, CA], 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Peaceweaving [Erie, PA], 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Plowshares movement
    - Disarmament action chronologies, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Thames River Plowshares, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Trident submarines [clippings], 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - United States Department of Defense [clippings], 1993-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - United States Department of Energy, Stockpile Stewardship and Management, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Witness for Disarmament [New Haven, CT]
    - Flyers, 1987-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Newsletters and minutes, 1989-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous [newsletters, flyers, brochures], 1987-1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-073
  Files created and kept by the War Resister's League New England (WRLNE) comprise the accession. The records supplement the Demonstrations section of Series I in the main accession. As one of the groups that founded the coalition, the WRLNE played an active role in planning, organizing, and carrying out protests against the production of nuclear weapons, primarily submarines, in Connecticut. Arranged chronologically by demonstration, the files include correspondence, memoranda, clippings, press releases, flyers, notes, and other materials documenting the demonstrations and protests against nuclear weaponry in Connecticut. The files particularly reflect the work of Joanne Sheehan, one of the leaders in several groups involved in these demonstrations. One folder of clippings spanning several years and regarding defense contracts between the Electric Boat Company and the United States government is filed at the end of the listing.
  - USS Ohio launching, 1979 April
    - General (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Endorsements (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Flyers (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Publicity (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Related actions (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - USS Michigan launching, 1980 April
    - General (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - USS Baltimore launching, 1980 December (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - USS Corpus Christi launching, 1981 April
    - General (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - USS Ohio commissioning and Florida launching, 1981 November (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Corpus Christi campaign [Community for Creative Non-Violence, Washington, DC], 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Trident Nein [nuclear activist group]
    - General (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - USS Michigan commissioning, 1982 September (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - USS Georgia launching, 1982 November (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - USS Corpus Christi commissioning [newspaper clippings], 1983 January (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Electric Boat blockade [newspaper clippings], 1983 March (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - USS Minneapolis-St.Paul launching, 1983 March
    - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Groton Peace Party [civil disobedience action by seminary students, Good Friday vigil], 1983 March (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - USS Albaquerque commissioning, 1983 March (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - USS Florida commissioning and International Day of Disarmament, 1983 June
    - General (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - USS Rickover launching [clippings], 1983 August (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Women of Faith [anti-nuclear activist group, non-violent civil disobedience], 1983 October (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - USS Rhode Island/Jackson launching, 1983 October (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - USS Augusta launching [clippings], 1983, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - USS Georgia commissioning, 1984 February (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - USS Minneapolis-St. Paul commissioning, 1984 March (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - USS Alabama launching, 1984 May (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
  - USS Providence launching, 1984 August (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - New England rally [nationwide actions], 1984 September (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Trident II Plowshares [anti-nuclear protest group], 1984 October (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - USS Jackson commissioning, 1984 October (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Harvest of Life or Harvest of Shame [non-violent march on Electric Boat shipyard], 1984 October (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - USS Pittsburgh launching, 1984 December (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Women of Faith [anti-nuclear activist group, winter solstice gathering], 1984 December (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - USS Alaska launching, 1985 January (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Good Friday vigil [Yale University Divinity School], 1985 April (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - USS Alabama commissioning, 1985 May (Box 3, Folder 45-46)
  - USS Nevada launching, 1985 September
    - General (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - USS Louisville launching, 1985 December (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Mobilization for Survival, Campaign Against Arms Build-up at Sea, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - USS Alaska commissioning, 1986 January (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Good Friday vigil [protest at Electric Boat], 1986 February-March (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - USS Helena launching, 1986 June (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Coalition to Stop Trident "Kick-off" [event marking the formation of CST], 1986 August (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - USS Nevada launching, 1986 August
    - General (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - October 25th Coalition [rally at New Haven Green], 1986 October (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - USS Louisville commissioning, 1986 November (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Mobilization for Survival 10th Anniversary Convention, 1986 November (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - USS Tennessee launching, 1986 December
    - General (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Miscellaneous demonstrations [Bike for Peace, Anniversary of Hiroshima bombing], 1986 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Lenten Witness for Disarmament, 1987 February-April (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Mobilization for Justice and Peace, 1987 April (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Walk for Life, 1987 August-September (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Anti-nuclear protest at Mystic, 1987 September (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - John Doe #5 [unnamed protester at Nautilus Memorial Museum], 1987 October (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Rally Against Trident, 1987 October
    - General (Box 4, Folder 68-69)
    - Clippings (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - "Back to the Brink" [demonstration and blockade], 1987 October (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Interfaith Pilgrimage [Japanese monks from Nipponzan Myohoji], 1987 October-November (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - USS Topeka launching, 1988 January (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - USS Pennsylvania launching, 1988 April (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - United Nations Third Special Session on Disarmament, 1988 June (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - USS San Juan launching, 1988 August (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - USS San Juan commissioning and Hiroshima Day, 1988 August (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - USS Miami launching, 1988 November (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - USS Tennessee commissioning, 1988 December (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Martin Luther King Day action, 1989 January (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Pax Christi Trident action, 1989 May (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - USS West Virginia launching, 1989 August (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - USS Pennsylvania commissioning, 1989 September (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Thames River Plowshares [raid on USS Pennsylvania], 1989 September-March (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - USS Kentucky launching, 1990 August (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - USS Boston launching, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Trident defense contracts [clippings], 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 87)
- Additional Material, Accession 2000-M-087
  The accession includes clippings, flyers, mailings, and pamphlets that supplement materials found in earlier accessions.
  - Clippings, 1980-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Mailings, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets and flyers, 1981-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional Material, Accession 2001-M-028
  - Atlantic Life Community [clippings and flyers re: Lenten Witness for Disarmament], 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Trident Nein
    - Clippings and flyers, 1982-1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Court trial transcripts, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3-10)
  - Clippings (misc.), 1980s (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - Flyers, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Poster [depicts the damaged hull of the USS Florida, the target of the Trident Nein action], ca. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Additional Material, Accession 2001-M-029
  The addition consists of the Trident Resistor's Handbook, a publication written, compiled, and edited by Bob Aldridge of the Pacific Life Research Center. The handbook provides background on the Trident and other military systems, as well as suggestions on organizing against them.
  - Trident Resistor's Handbook
    - Cover page, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Table of Contents, Foreword, and Preface, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Section 1: Understanding the New World Order, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Section 2: The Trident Submarine and Missile System, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Section 3: Supporting Systems, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Section 4: Trident Deployment, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Section 5: The Hazards of Trident, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Section 6: Trident Economics, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Section 7: Nuclear Weapons Inventories, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Section 8: Other Military Systems, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Section 9: Nonviolent Resistance and Alternatives to Military Force, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Pacific Life Research Center Papers, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Glossary, Bibliography, and Appendices, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Record of revisions, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - September 1995 revisions (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - March 1996 revisions (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Autumn 1996 revisions (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Additional Material, Accession 2001-M-067
  This addition contains organizational notes on the Lenten Witness for Disarmament movement, as well as various flyers and correspondence relating to other disarmament movements in Connecticut. The organizational notes and clippings help give a closer glimpse into the workings of this movement.
  - Advent Peace Witness (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Franciscan Community (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lenten Witness for Disarmament
    - General, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 5)
    - Clippings, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fliers, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Writings [proposals, meeting notes], undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Nuclear programs in Connecticut, 1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous [sermons, articles], 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, Accession 2002-M-104
  The accession consists of correspondence, clippings, flyers, meeting minutes, and other material produced or collected by the Trident/Conversion Campaign, one of the earlier groups resisting the Trident program in Connecticut.
  - Clippings
    - General, 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
    - Electric Boat road closing, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Marine Draftmen's Association strike, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Conversion Planner [newsletter], 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 8)
    - Fisher, Peter, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Stolberg, Irving J., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - EB Topics [General Dynamics newsletter], 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - EB Real Topics [General Dynamics newsletter], 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "The Empty Pork Barrel: Unemployment and the Pentagon Budget", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Flyers, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Labor issues [pamphlets, flyers, clippings], 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 15 - 16)
  - Lucas Aerospace, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - McGovern-Matthias Bill, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Meeting minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 19 - 20)
  - Mid-Peninsula Conversion Project, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Religious Conference on Disarmament and Peace, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Religious task force, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "The Soviet Threat: Answers for Peace Activists" [by Marta Daniels], 1978 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-062
  - Administrative records, 1983-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aldridge, Bob [correspondence, writings, and background information about the Trident protest movement], 1992-1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Peace Test, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Protest information [flyers, mailings, clippings, and other materials], 1976-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 4 - 6)
  - Responses by Electric Boat workers to protest handouts, 1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Trident missiles and submarines [technical information], 1984-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Additional Material, 1960-1987; Accession 2007-M-086
  Materials document Coalition to Stop Trident activities protesting the General Dynamics subsidiary, Electric Boat, in Groton, Connecticut, as well as more general anti-nuclear activities in the New England area. Materials were given to the donor by Michelle Zacks, one of the founding coalition members, after she discovered them while in the process of moving from the New Haven area.
  - Coalition to Stop Trident organizing papers, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Electric Boat
    - Clippings, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Gary Koos alternative use study, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - General Dynamics, 1966, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Leaflets, originals, Circa 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Protests, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Veliotis, P. Takis, scandal, clippings, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Harvest of Life, 1984 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - National/other area press, Circa 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - New England Committee for Non-Violent Action, 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Submarines, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Trident information, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12 - 13, Reel `)
  - Trident Nein newsletter, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Trident II Plowshares, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Handouts/flyers concerning efforts to halt production and deployment of Trident submarines and missiles in Connecticut and New England., 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Additional Material, Accession 2010-M-076
  - Poster, "Disarmament/Trident Nein, July 5, 1982", 1982 July 5 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1964-2009; Accession 2015-M-039; 0.02; (1 envelope)
  - Photographs of protests, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)